Pierre-Luc Nichols

London, UK 07 472 372 972 pierrelucnichols@gmail.com www.plnichols.com

PROFILE

Dev: HTML5 - CSS3 - Sass - Javascript - AngularJS - jQuery - Jasmine - Ajax - Json - PHP - JSP **Tools**: Git - Grunt - Gulp - Adobe - Terminal - Node - npm - Wordpress - Eclipse - SVN - Jenkins **Expertise**: front end dev - responsive - user experience - unit tests - cross-browser - agile - scrum **About me**: motivated - professional - organised - team player - quick learner - attention to detail

EXPERIENCE

UI Developer, William Hill (contract) (2014 to now - Gibraltar & London, UK)

- Project UI lead front end developer for the new responsive cross device pages of williamhill.com
- Extensive refactoring of CSS styles and new modular architecture of Angular JS/html templates
- · Angular JS development and unit tests of components, directives, filters using Karma/Jasmine

Front End Software Engineer, Marks & Spencer (2014 - London, UK)

- Optimisation of the new M&S eCommerce platform for desktop, tablet and mobile devices
- •In charge of implementing a new modular CSS architecture driven by Sass pre-processor
- · Content & Editorial lead developer doing responsive web design and AngularJS development

Front End Developer, Yellow Pages Group (2012 to 2013 - Montreal, CA)

- · Lead front end for Canpages real estate website and Yellow Pages 360 responsive Wordpress site
- Performance optimisation of mobile websites and development in an agile/scrum environment

Front End Developer, Sid Lee Technologies (2012 - Montreal, CA)

- · Lead front end developer at CBC (Canadian Broadcasting Company) for Olympics 2012 website
- ·CBC homepage re-design (radio-canada.ca) Facebook page, mobile and Wordpress development

Front End Developer, Hybris Software (2011 to 2012 - Montreal, CA)

- •HTML/CSS/JS development of eCommerce websites for national and international brands
- · Responsible for testing, cross-browser compatibility, optimisation and improvements to code base

Web developer, Calypso Communication (2005 to 2010 - St-Hyacinthe, CA)

• Full stack web development using PHP, MySQL, jQuery, HTML, CSS, Wordpress, Joomla, etc...

Freelance (2001 to now)

• Design, UX, front end development, SEO, performance optimisation

EDUCATION

PHP Object Oriented Programming, 2012 IT Institute, Maisonneuve College, Montreal, Qc, Canada AJAX Programming/Development, 2009 IT Institute, Maisonneuve College, Montreal, Qc, Canada AEC Communications and IT, 1999-2000 St-Hyacinthe CEGEP, St-Hyacinthe, Qc, Canada